<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Community - Tag - TechZerker</title><link>https://techzerker.com/tags/community/</link><description>Community - Tag - TechZerker</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://techzerker.com/tags/community/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Toxicity in Linux Community (Link)</title><link>https://techzerker.com/2021-02-11-toxic-linux/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://techzerker.com/2021-02-11-toxic-linux/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="https://medium.com/linuxforeveryone" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer"><em>Linux For Everyone</em></a> channel, founded by <a href="https://layer8.space/@killyourfm" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Jason Evangelho</a> today posted an excellent commentary, written by <a href="https://schykle.medium.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Alan Diggs</a> on the recurring challenges of the <a href="https://medium.com/linuxforeveryone/windows-is-sh-t-linux-users-and-the-technical-superiority-problem-196a597aa860" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">toxicity in the Linux community</a>.</p>
<p>While there are some amazing and supportive groups throughout the Linux community, it is easy to agree with this commentary that the toxicity is a scar that consistently hurts the overall image of Linux and Open Source.</p>
<p>Working in enterprise IT, I personally know a selection of working IT folks who at my encouragement have <em>tried</em> Linux, and if they couldn&rsquo;t reach me, gone to a forum for questions, and then texted me <em>quitting Linux</em> because of how agressivly they were berated.</p>
<p>My core approach with Linux and encouraging adoption has been to talk about my own system and what works (and what does not) and show it off a little. If anyone reaches out and shows some interest, I will gadly answer what questions I can, understand their needs, and attempt to help and steer them in the right direction. However, the core philosphy is:</p>
<blockquote>
<p><em>Use what works for you. Period.</em></p>
</blockquote>
<p>If your Windows 10 system is getting the job (or game) done for you, and anything the community has shown in Linux (or BSD) has not grabbed your attention, that&rsquo;s fine, live and let live. If your interested in the systems the positive users in the community talk about and demonstrate, reach out with questions. If you&rsquo;ve tried before and hit a <em>&ldquo;Wall of Toxicity&rdquo;</em>, then here are a few great places to join and ask questions where we&rsquo;ll be friendly and helpful, regardless of your experience level:</p>
<p><a href="https://fosstodon.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer"><strong>Fosstodon</strong></a> (Mastodon Instance)</p>
<p><a href="https://t.me/linux4everyone" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer"><strong>Telegram: Linux For Everyone</strong></a></p>]]></description></item></channel></rss>